

Rahul mani tripathi

TEAM LEAD

I am an expert m obile and web application developer with over 10 years of experience in And roid and i OS development. I have handled both consumer and enterprise applications and possess a solid b ack gro und in c re ating com plex m obile applications for And roid and i OS using n ative technologies or React Native, as well as developing portals with React.js

 \searrow

Rahulma n it5 @ q m a il.co m

П

+91-9540269422



Gorakhpur UP



AERA OF EXPERTISE

Javascript – 8+ yrs

TypeScript - 3 yrs

React Native – 8yrs

React JS-8 yrs

Unit Testing – 1yrs

Redux-4 yrs

Next JS - 3yrs

Node JS-4yrs

EXPERIENCE

NOV 2024 - Present

Senior Lead, Software Full Stack Engineer Northern Trust, PUNE

- Integrated OKTA for Authentication
- Upgrade XPS version
- UI/UX Bug fixes and new feature Implementation
- ODS service API integration

SEP 2021 - OCT 2024

TEAM LEAD, Xetech Private Limited, Noida

- Assisted with the develOpment Of Trudoc app using React native
- Integrated BLE Enabled Medical devices with App.
- Integrate Vydeo sdk for video call.
- Integrate multiple payment gateway approved by client.
- Task allocation to team members.
- Mobile Api development.
- POC's created for client.
- UI Design, Code merging.
- Write unit testing code.
- Push notification custom UI implementation for answer and decline call feature
- Picture In picture Implantation using native module
- Create custom hooks.

OCT 2019 - SEP 2021

Software Developer, ITH Technologies, Kanpur

- Deal with Trade dog App (Android kotlin) MVVM Architecture
- UI and Crypto API implementation for Trade Dog APP (React Native & Node JS)
- Block Chain wallet payment Integration
- Deal With Oshodhara App (React Native)
- UI & Logic implementation
- Architecture setup for app
- Razorpay payment gateway implementation
- Bed allocation all logic according to gender, agegroup, for family implementation
- Deal with Airpurifier App (React Native) UI and logic implementation for ON/OFF feature read/write data to device and display graph according to data.
- Connection of Hardware air purifier using BLE and controlling of hardware using APP.

APR 2015 - OCT 2019

Software Developer, Mine Solution PVT LTD, KANPUR

- Design and develop MyCleanCity APP (React Native & Node JS).
- Google map integration.
- Marker selection and drawing area on map like polygon or rectangle.
- Display ORAC data in List and In map view.
- Print google map marker selection area in PDF.
- Arcgis Map Integration
- Faciltator app Design and develop for Mycleancity app.
- Task Allocation for facilitator and acceptance of task
- Push notification implementation
- Deal with dimamzo food delivery app (Android, java)
- User APP, Restaurant app, Admin App
- EasyForSure website (PHP,CodeIgnitor)

.

Projects

- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.youclick.wecare
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.savana
- https://apps.apple.com/nl/app/mycleancity/id1272757352
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dimamzo
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=io.tradedog
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=savana.facilitator
- https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/trudoc24x7-sa/id1605109951
- https://www.easyforsure.com/index.php
- Find a doctor easily (healthxafrica.com) (React js)
- TruDoc | Always with You (trudocgroup.com) (React js)
- Trailboss Advantage Log in Trailboss Advantage (trailbossinc.com) (React is)
- Virtual Clinic APP, Oshodhara App, Airpurifire APP, Fantasy APP
 (These apps are not uploaded because they are for internal use or not approved by playstore)

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Graduation: B.tech(computer science & engg.)
2009 to 2013

From U.P.Technical University, I.I.T.M. College, Kanpur

Aggregate: 72.55%

> Intermediate:

2007

From P.N.M. Inter College (U.P. Board) with (P.C.M.)

Aggregate: 67.00%

Matriculation:

2005

From P.N.M Inter College (U.P. Board) in Science Stream with math's, science

Aggregate: 59.50%

KEY SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES

- Emotionally stable person.
- Analytical and Reasoning skills
- Strong Will Power.

• Ability to work for long hours.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender : Male

Date of Birth : 10-DEC-1991 Nationality : Indian Marital Status : Single Father's Name :

: Mr. Ramesh Mani Tripathi

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Bhojpuri

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to my knowledge. I am also confident enough above my ability to work in a team & prove my ability.

Date:

(RAHUL MANI TRIPATHI)

Place: